Hey everybody, thank you for coming back
and being with us for another episode of
Three Questions where we meet women in
the PCA and we get to hear about how God
is using their ministry in the kingdom.
So, we get to meet somebody entirely new
today and I'm going to let her introduce
herself. Take it away. Hi, my name is
Judy Pucket and um I live in
Westminster, Maryland, which is a a
rural town in Northern Maryland and I
serve at Chapelgate Presbyterian Church
uh as the director of spiritual
formation for women, but more
importantly, I have three wonderful
children and a wonderful husband and we
live on a small farm.
>> Oh, I want to hear just a little bit
more about that. What's on the farm?
It's just a hobby farm and we have beef
cattle
>> and so we have delicious meat. Um but
we're just small. We only have like
right now we only have 11 head of
cattle. But it is a great hobby and we
love to just watch the cows.
>> Yes.
>> And it's great except when they get out
and are being stubborn and then it's
horrible.
>> Yeah, that sounds horrible but I love
the picture that it forms in my head.
Okay, so here are three questions. tell
your little corner of the kingdom and
what you're doing there. Let's just
start with that one.
>> Okay. So, at Chapelgate, like I said, I
serve as the director of spiritual
formation for women. And that includes
um like the joy of being able to lead
and craft Bible studies and counsel
women and um plan events and speak and
teach at conferences. But I think what
has been really exciting over the past
couple years is for me to see women rise
to places of leadership in the church
and to see men and women work together
>> in the kingdom work and to um move past
like maybe some of the fears that come
with men and women serving together in
leadership and to just see how that's
kind of exploded
>> at Chapelgate and kind of as a result of
the shepher shepherdist ministry. Um,
which I know we're going to talk about
in a little bit.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's what Okay. I
would love to hear about a way you've
seen God use you, but I I have prepped
her that I want her to talk specifically
about this ministry. So, yes, please
talk about it.
>> Sure. So during the pandemic, actually
several months before the pandemic, um I
had the honor of leading a team of both
men and women, elders and women. And one
pastor was on our team in establishing a
shepherdist ministry. And this ministry
exists to walk alongside women in the
church who are in crisis or distress.
And it's a collaborative ministry where
an elder and a shepherdist work together
to provide a care team for a woman who
is in crisis. And those cases can
include domestic abuse,
>> infidelity. We've seen a lot of issues
with gender identity in marriages and
also with children.
>> And it it can also include ca cancer or
a major life change. the the gamut is
wide on the kinds of issues that we see.
But what's beautiful, Christine, is that
often the presence like a woman
interacting with a man is awkward
>> and uncomfortable without the presence
of another woman in some of these
situations, especially in cases of
abuse.
>> Oh, right.
>> So, um it's it's necessary. I I believe
every church should have a ministry like
this where elders and women leaders are
working together to care for the women
of our church because these women are in
all of our churches.
>> These women who are are being abused or
have been in abusive relationships or
are struggling with gender identity
issues, they are in our churches. The
church is not exempt from these kind of
of of issues. And we need to be able to
step into the mess.
>> Yes. to to be trained, to be equipped,
and then to recognize we don't we don't
know what we're doing really, but you
know, to rely on the spirit to equip us
to walk alongside women who are hurting.
>> And I'm assuming there have already been
churches that are hearing and are like,
"Hey, how do we how do we do this?" And
what do you tell them? Do you just is
there something some package you can
deliver? Do you go train them? What do
you tell them when they ask?
>> Kind of all of those things. So we we
began with a model that Christ's
Covenant Church in in Matthews, North
Carolina, they were doing this and so we
kind of looked we used them as a
template and then we contextualized that
for Chapelgate and it took us quite a
while to do that because as you know
every church is different and what works
perfectly in one context doesn't work
perfectly in every context. So, what I
um what I tell people and and this has
been one of the most awesome parts is
that pastors are asking like, "Hey, how
do we do this?"
>> Um, and Mike has done a great job of
connecting me with some of them. And
sometimes it involves like they just
want my resources. They just want
documents. And that's fine. I'm happy to
send them. often we'll have a Zoom call
or a couple where we'll just begin
talking and they can kind of rapidfire
pepper questions to me. There's a
church, another PCA church in our town
and I went and visited with them and
kind of did some training and met with
some of their women leaders and their
pastor and we just kind of talked
through and a lot of times it it's just
a lot of questions because they really
need to see how is this going to work
for our church.
>> Yes. And I I like to provide them some
resources and if they want I'm happy to
come and do some training and then let
them kind of get their hands in it, you
know, and really see how is this going
to work for for us.
>> Yes, that's my canon, right? For anybody
who doesn't know Travelgate at all. So,
if if somebody might be watching this
and thinking, "Oh my goodness, I want
that or I want to know more." What's the
best way to for them to find you? To
just go to Chapelgate and find you on
the website or Okay.
>> Yep. They can find my email address
there and um they can reach out to me
and I would love to connect with them.
>> What's your What's Chapelgate's website?
>> chapelgate.org.
>> Awesome. Easy. Okay.
>> So helpful. I have a feeling I mean
obviously we all need a program like
this. Yes. And so if you're listening,
you don't have one, this is a great
place to start. Okay. Third question.
What can we, your brothers and sisters
in the PCA, I'm thinking now as we're
recording, lots of our brothers and
sisters are at General Assembly.
>> What can we do to encourage you in your
work just in general? What can we as a
denomination do as individuals? What
would help?
You know, I think one of the the most
important things, the the biggest prayer
requests that I have is that men and
women would move past any barriers
or fears or whatever it is to seeing
women in leadership in the church.
>> It's been my experience and and maybe
yours too that women aren't looking to
take over. They aren't looking to become
elders and pastors, but they do have a
voice and it's an important one and it's
one that needs to be heard. And in a lot
of these situations, I mean,
Chapelgate's been such a blessing
because, you know, the elders and the
pastors, they'll come to my team of
women leaders and they'll say like,
"Okay, we don't know what we're doing.
We don't know how to enter into this."
>> And that spirit of humility and and need
and desire. It's so beautiful,
Christine. And I that's my biggest
prayer is that pastors would step
forward and say, "Hey, not like what can
we let our women do?" I absolutely hate
the question.
>> Yes.
>> But
>> we need our women. We need them and we
want their voice and we're a family and
the family works best when everyone is
working and collaborating together.
>> And so that's really my my prayer for
our denomination is that we would see it
not not as a threat but as something
beautiful and glorious and and and such
a amazing picture of the gospel on
display. And it's got to be just to see
the movement of um sort of us versus
them to like brother and sister together
has to be so encouraging and see the
gift and the love and respect and
>> it's got to be.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much. Thank you for being
willing to just give us just a little
bit of just a little peak into what's
going on there and and the resources and
thanks for your willingness. I
appreciate it.
>> Sure. I was happy to do it.